## Name

# Mtendere C. Nkhoma

## **Contact**

#### Address:

C/O Chifundo Nkhoma One Acre Fund Malawi Zomba.

#### Phone:

- +265 (0) 999 139 779
- +265 (0) 884 090 858

#### Email:

mtenderenkhoma@gmail.com

# Languages

English Chichewa Tumbuka Tonga

# **Summary**

Over 14 years of training and experience in ICT; management, support & user training. Proficient in Cloud based Systems, Networking, Server administration, and Operating Systems installation, configuration & administration as well as good troubleshooting skills. Effective communicator and a quick learner, able to support and train users to be competent in resolving simple and common ICT issues on a computer and other common devices. Conducts target setting, profiling and performance monitoring to meet priorities of business and customers. Holder of Bachelor of Science Information Communication Technology with Mzuzu University, among other qualifications and skills.

# Skill and Knowledge Highlights

- Administration of a Cloud based System for loan management
- Windows Server 2021 R2 Active Directory Administration
- Network Managent using Mikrotik and Ubiquiti networking devices
- Microsoft Office 365 services management
- Network installation, configuration and maintenance
- Virtualization
- Printers, Operating Systems, Software & Hardware installation and maintenance
- Sage Accounting and Sage VIP Payroll system support
- Website development in Python, HTML & PHP
- On-Site & Off-Site Technical Support
- User training
- User Support Documentation Composition
- Internal and External ICT/Financial Audit Support
- Knowledge in CISCO networking (Self Study)
- Database Administration using MySQL
- Knowledge in Project Management

# **Experience**

**IT Support Officer** - 09/2016 to 07/2021 **Microloan Foundation**, Lilongwe

- Administration of a Cloud based Microfinance Management System called Musoni in liaison with the system developers.
- User support (as a Help Desk Officer for Microloan Foundation nationwide) on-sight as well as remotely using TeamViewer.
- Management and troubleshooting LAN and internet connectivity using Mikrotik router, Ubiquiti access points and switches

- Collaborating with ISP's on internet service provision quality
- Installation and maintenance of all hardware and software in the organization nationwide. Network installation, configuration and administration.
- Ensure all Security and Application programs are licensed and facilitate license procurement from reputable suppliers
- Windows Server 2012 Microsoft Active Directory administration.
- Server and Operating Systems virtualization
- Managing Microsoft SQL Server; backups and maintenance.
- Managing Microsoft Office 365 in liaison with the IT Manager.
- Managing Sage Accounting, create system backups and user management in liaison with the HR & IT Manager.
- Support and troubleshoot Sage VIP Premier payroll system used by HR department.
- Conduct Staff training on how to use the Cloud Based Microfinance System, PC usage training, Windows OS and All Microsoft Office Applications, as well as proper use of android tablets).
- Manage the NAS Offsite backup systems for servers.
- ICT Policy enforcement to all users nationwide
- Plan and manage various ICT projects instituted by the ICT department of Management in liaison with the ICT Manager
- Develop and implement System disaster recovery plans to maintain business continuity
- Create User manuals for All Computer Applications used in Microloan Foundation.
- Liaise with the ICT Manager on establishing better ICT working environment for all users.
- IT Asset management and record keeping. Procurement of ICT equipment in reason with the Procurement Officer.
- Support External ICT Audits (by EY) as well as internal audits in provision of relevant data and records as required
- Help formulate the ICT annual budget plans with the ICT Manager

#### ICT Teacher - 10/2013 to 08/2016

#### Joyce Banda Foundation High School, Blantyre

- Teaching IGCSE ICT (All classes)
- Teaching MANEB Computer Studies
- Network Administration (entire institution)
- Software and Hardware installation & maintenance support (for the whole institution)
- Computer Security (Anti-virus installation & updating)
- Monitoring and controlling the use of computers
- Computer System Installations and Maintenance
- End user support (Support all staff on computer usage and provide maintenance support to all users)
- Part of the Exams committee to perform all computerized procedures in the administration of IGCSE exams in the institution such as student exams registration, queries and results retrieval

#### **ICT Lecture –** 5/2011 to 9/2013

#### International College of Business Management, Blantyre

- Lecturing Diploma and Certificate courses in Information Communication Technology and Business Information Systems
- Local Area Network Administration
- Software and Hardware maintenance
- Computer Security (Anti-virus installation & updating)
- Monitoring and controlling the use of computers
- User training e.g. Microsoft office Suite applications
- Computer System Installations and Maintenance

#### Data Officer - 2009 - 2011

#### Winners' Chapel International, Lilongwe

- Software and Hardware Installation and Maintenance
- Graphics and designing
- Monitoring the use of Computers and ensuring security
- Data Entry
- Systems Information Security (Antivirus installation and updating)
- Basic procurement

#### IT Lecturer - 2007 to 2009

#### Mission Resource Centre, Lilongwe

- Lecturing in IT courses in Diploma and Certificate classes
- Teaching computer packages e.g. Microsoft office programs
- Monitoring and controlling the use of computers
- Computer security (Antivirus installation and updating)
- Promoting the importance of using computers, how to use and operate it
- Demonstrating competence in computer maintenance through keeping computer laboratory and computer equipment clean and report any malfunction to relevant authorities.

#### **Education**

- Bachelor of Science: Information Communication Technology –
  2020, Mzuzu University
- Diploma: Information System Analysis and Design 2008
  Mission Resource Center, Lilongwe
- Certificate: Information Technology and Programming 2007
  Mission Resource Center, Lilongwe
- Certificate: Malawi School Certificate of Education 2005
  Bunda Institute of Education, Lilongwe

## **Success Stories**

- Involved in institution and implementation of tablet scanning project which was aimed at formulation a paperless and fast Loan Application and disbursement process. I perform all tablet configurations and conduct training to all new recruits on how to use the new processes.
- Help a key role in digitizing field documents as well as the loan approval process in the Microfinance Management System. Formulated upload centers in the system and trained all users nationwide on the new developments
- Developed a Web based School Management system during System projects at Mzuzu University which was a success as it was accredited to be a good replacement of the current system if modified to meet school requirements.

## Referees

#### Manase Chiwaya

P.O. Box 2601, Lilongwe. Phone: +265 (0) 884 619 900

# Misheck Nyirenda The HOD ICT Department

Mzuzu University Private Bag 201, Mzuzu 2. Phone: +265 (0) 999 259 325

#### Bisani Banda

P.O. Box 2601, Lilongwe. Phone: +265 (0) 992 969 307